Menu

Privacy Policy
==============

Privacy Policy for the Thermomix® Recipe Platform (Cookidoo®), the Thermomix® App and the Thermomix®
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Date: March 2022

### Content

1. [General](#General)
2. [Platform](#Platform)
3. [Thermomix®](#Thermomix)
4. [Tracking of Usage Behaviour](#TrackingofUsageBehaviour)
5. [Customer Care](#CustomerCare)
6. [Payment Data](#PaymentData)
7. [Email Marketing](#EmailMarketing)
8. [Recipients of Personal Data](#RecipientsofPersonalData)
9. [Your Rights](#YourRights)
10. [Data Security](#DataSecurity)
11. [Retention and Deletion of Data by Vorwerk International](#RetentionandDeletionofDatabyVorwerkInternational)
12. [Status of the Privacy Policy](#StatusofthePrivacyPolicy)
13. [Data Protection Officer](#DataProtectionOfficer)

### 1 General

**1.1** The following provisions determine how Vorwerk International & Co. KmG, Verenastrasse 39, CH-8832 Wollerau, Schweiz (“Vorwerk International”) and Vorwerk, LLC, 3255 Thousand Oaks Blvd., Thousand Oaks, CA 91362 (“Local Vorwerk Entity”, both companies together the “Vorwerk Group Companies”) handle your personal data with regard to the website “Thermomix® Recipe Platform” (“Cookidoo®”), the Thermomix® mobile app “TM App” (“App”, Cookidoo® and the App collectively the “Platform”) and the “Vorwerk Thermomix®”, a kitchen device with optional internet connection (“Thermomix®”). The sale of the Thermomix® is supported by a team of Thermomix® advisors (“Thermomix® Advisor”) who also organize cooking demonstrations and other events, providing professional presentations and first-hand experiences with regard to the use of the Thermomix® and The Platform

**1.2** Vorwerk Group Companies in the instances described below in the Privacy Policy act as joint controllers (please see para. 4.4.3, 4.4.5, 4.5.3, 4.5.4, 7.3, 8.3), whenever you have been asked to provide additional consent for data processing (“Tracking on the Platform”; “Tracking on the Thermomix”; “Email marketing”; “Synchronisation and Update of Customer Data between Vorwerk Group Companies”) that covers transfer of data between Vorwerk International and Local Vorwerk Entity and the Thermomix® Advisor.

**1.3** Vorwerk International is the provider of the Platform, whereas the Local Vorwerk Entity distributes the Thermomix®.

**1.4** Detailed information about the handling of your data is provided below in this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions or comments, please contact the data protection officer via the contact information provided in section 13 below.

**1.5** You can access this privacy information at any time within the App, retrieve it from Cookidoo® at Privacy Policy or, if the Thermomix® is connected with the Internet, access it in the Thermomix® in the menu Settings | Privacy | Privacy policy.

**1.6** Vorwerk International is the data controller with regard to all data processed as described in the following. However, in certain cases described in this Privacy Policy, data may be transferred to other legal entities which will then be data processor of such transferred data. Detailed information about the handling of your data is provided below in the policy under section 8 “Recipients of personal data”.

**1.7** We do not sell personal information.

### 2 Platform

**2.1** The following provisions of this section 2 only apply to the use of the Platform and the Thermomix®. Both components of the Platform, Cookidoo® and the App provide identical functionality; thus, the App and Cookidoo® are treated identically in this section 2.

**2.2** If you download the App as Apple iOS version, the download will be processed via the App store “iTunes” operated by Apple, Inc., 1 Infinite Loop, Cupertino, California 95014, USA (“Apple, Inc”) for the purpose of operating the App, and the data will be transferred to Apple, Inc. For further information on the processing of your data by Apple, Inc., please go to [https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy](https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy)/.

**2.3** If you download the App as Android version, the download will be processed via the App store “Google Play” operated by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, California 94043, USA (“Google LLC”) for the purpose of operating the App, and the data will be transferred to Google LLC. For further information on the processing of your data by Google Inc., please go to [https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy)/.

**2.4** Use of the Platform Without Registered Account

**2.4.1** When the Platform is accessed, for technical reasons, the following data will automatically be transmitted to Vorwerk International:

* IP address
* Date and time
* Accessing device and browser
* Operating system running on the accessing device
* A notification of whether access was successful

**2.4.2** The foregoing data will be processed to technically enable you to use the Platform. Additionally, the data may be evaluated for statistical purposes and to improve the service offered in an anonymous form. Such data is processed on the legal basis of legitimate interest (Art. 6 (1) f GDPR); business purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(d) CCPA).

**2.4.3** On the Platform, you may browse through recipes without a registered account in a limited preview mode. In this case, the following functions are provided among others on the website:

* Browse the website
* Search for recipes
* Open recipe previews
* Learn about the products offered by Vorwerk
* Read editorial content such as articles

**2.4.4** Such data is processed on the legal basis of legitimate interest (Art. 6 (1) f GDPR); business purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(d) CCPA).

**2.5** Use of the Platform With a Registered Account

**2.5.1** Before being able to use the full scope of the Platform, you have to create a user account. For this purpose, the following data will be requested (\* = required data for the registration, other fields are optional):

* Email address\*
* Password\*
* Country of residence\*
* Name, surname
* Language

**2.5.2** The foregoing data is required in order to provide the following functions:

* Create and administer the user account
* Create my own recipes (Created recipes)
* Create custom recipe lists in order to collect, organize and bookmark recipes
* Create shopping lists
* Save recipe collections created by Vorwerk International
* Plan recipes for a day to cook them (weekly planner)
* Purchase and administration of a Cookidoo® subscription, purchase of further products

**2.5.3** The use of all such foregoing functions is optional. Such data is processed on the legal basis of the performance of a contract (Art. 6 (1) b GDPR); business purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(d) CCPA).

**2.5.4** Each account registration involves creation of customer profile. User may optionally provide additional information about food preferences in order to receive better search results when looking for recipes. In addition, the user may save a selection of other filters that will be also used during recipes search. The foregoing data is being collected through your profile:

* Profile picture
* Cooking style
* Search filter preferences
* Household size

**2.5.5** The use of all such foregoing functions is optional. Such data is processed on the legal basis of the performance of a legitimate interest (Art. 6 (1) f GDPR); business purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(d) CCPA).

**2.6** Assignment of a Thermomix® with Your Cookidoo® Account

**2.6.1** If you own a Thermomix® TM5 with a Cook-Key®, you may optionally assign your Thermomix® with your Cookidoo® account by entering the serial number of your Thermomix® device to your Account.

**2.6.2** If you own a Thermomix® TM6, you may optionally assign your Thermomix® TM6 with your Cookidoo® account via built in Wi-Fi. In order to do that during the log in process on Thermomix® you enter credentials from your Cookidoo account.

**2.6.3** If your Thermomix® is connected to the internet (see section 3.4 below), you may then transfer recipes available on your Cookidoo® account to your Thermomix®. Such data is processed on the legal basis of the performance of a contract (Art. 6 (1) b GDPR); business purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(d) CCPA).

**2.7** Cookies

We use cookies on the Platform in order to give you the best user experience when visiting it.. Cookies are sets of data which are stored by your web browser and which contain data. Please find all information on the use of cookies in our Cookie Policy, which can be accessed through a link that can be found in the footer of our webpages and in the App’s settings or the Cookie banner.

### 3 Thermomix®

**3.1** The following provisions of this section 3 do only apply to the use of the Thermomix®.

**3.2** In addition to the sections below, further data will be processed in case of an assignment of a Thermomix® with your Cookidoo® account. Please see section 2.6 with this regard.

**3.3** If you have given your consent for tracking of your usage behaviour, further data may be processed as outlined in section 4 below.

**3.4** Connection of a Thermomix® to the Internet

**3.4.1** When connecting a Thermomix® to the Internet, the data described in section 2.4.1 is processed to technically enable you to connect the Thermomix® with the internet and with the Platform.

**3.4.2** Additionally, the following data will be transferred to Vorwerk International:

* IP address
* MAC Address of Cook-Key®
* Serial Number of Cook-Key®
* Date and time
* Type of device ID used for logging
* Operating system running on the accessing device
* Selected country and language
* Notification of whether access was successful
* In case of failed connections, the reason for the failure in form of an error code

**3.4.3** It will be used there only in order to improve the quality of the Wi-Fi and the internet connectivity of the Thermomix® together with basic services such as firmware or modes update. Such data is processed on the legal basis of legitimate interest (Art. 6 (1) f GDPR); business purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(d) CCPA).

### 4 Tracking of Usage Behaviour

**4.1** We would like to better understand how you and other users of the Thermomix® use the Platform and the Thermomix® in order to improve our services and products. Also, we would like to provide you with content and offers matching your possible interests. For this purpose, we ask you for your consent in order to track your usage behaviour on the Platform and on the Thermomix®.

**4.2** We ask you separately for both tracking on the Platform and on the Thermomix® and you may give and withdraw your consent separately at any time. Refusal or revocation of such consent does not affect either the use of the Platform or of the Thermomix®.

**4.3** The data outlined in the following sections 4.4 and 4.5 below is processed on the legal basis of consent (Art. 6 (1) a GDPR); commercial purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(f) CCPA).

**4.4** Tracking On the Platform

**4.4.1** In case you have given your consent for tracking of your usage behaviour on the Platform, the following applies.

**4.4.2** When visiting the Platform, your following data will be collected by Vorwerk International:

* Your User ID
* Saved Collections
* Set and removed Bookmarks
* Food preferences
* Which screens or pages have been visited
* Which functions have been used
* Which recipes have been viewed
* Timestamp of each user interaction
* List of

* Collections of recipes that have been purchased or subscribed to
* Recipes that you plan to cook per day in “My Week”
* Products needed for the recipes in “Shopping list”

**4.4.3** The foregoing data will be transferred to the Local Vorwerk Entity and be used by the Vorwerk Group Companies for the following purposes:

* Enhance user experience when visiting the Platform
* Suggest and recommend more relevant content (such as recipes)
* Suggest similar recipe collections
* Filter search results
* Analytics of usage data
* Usage Data and Guided Cooking Data
* Insights about user behaviour and interaction with the Platform
* Improvement of services and products

**4.4.4** Based on the foregoing information, content and recommendations will be displayed on the Platform or on other websites or apps of the Vorwerk Group Companies (and within marketing emails, to the extent you additionally consented to the reception of such marketing emails).

**4.4.5** In addition to the foregoing, the Vorwerk Group Companies may provide your Thermomix® Advisor with a summary of the foregoing data about your use of the Platform. Based on the foregoing information, your Thermomix® Advisor may contact you in order to provide you with content and offers matching your possible interests; a contact via email will only take place to the extent you additionally consented to the reception of such marketing emails.

**4.4.6** You can find the exact wording of your consent declaration under Account | Data usage

**4.4.7** You can withdraw your consent at any time by changing your privacy settings in your account on the Platform. Go to “Data Usage” listed in the “Account” and move the bar to withdraw permission.

**4.5** Tracking On Your Thermomix®

**4.5.1** In case you have given your consent for tracking of your usage behaviour on the Thermomix®, the following applies.

**4.5.2** When connected to the Internet, the Thermomix® transfers the following data to Vorwerk International:

* IP address
* Thermomix® Serial Number
* User ID
* If applicable, Cook-Key® ID (MAC address)
* Latitude and longitude (approximation)
* Postal ZIP code (approximation)
* Functions or settings and its parameters used (e.g. cooking, stirring with revs/minute)
* Timestamp and duration of the functions used
* The data collected in the course of the connection of a Thermomix® to the internet as described in section 3.4.1
* Usage data per cooking session: User activities (e. g. which recipe has been cooked, which functions of the Thermomix® have been used)

**4.5.3** The foregoing data will be transferred to the Local Vorwerk Entity and be used by the Vorwerk Group Companies for the following purposes:

* Enhance user experience when using the Thermomix®
* Suggest and recommend more relevant content (such as recipes)
* Suggest similar recipe collections
* Filter search results
* Analytics of usage data
* Insights about user behaviour and interaction with the Platform and the Thermomix®
* Improvement of services and products
* Recommendation of relevant, personalized content

**4.5.4** In addition to the foregoing, the Vorwerk Group Companies may provide your Thermomix® Advisor with a summary of the foregoing data about your use of the Thermomix®. Based on the foregoing information, your Thermomix® Advisor may contact you in order to provide you with content and offers matching your possible interests; a contact via email will only take place to the extent you additionally consented to the reception of such marketing emails.

**4.5.5** The provisions of this section 4.5 do only apply to the use of the Thermomix® and data is being transmitted to Vorwerk only if the Thermomix® is connected with the Internet. They do not apply with regard to the use of the Platform.

**4.5.6** In case of using TM5 you can find the exact wording of your consent declaration under Settings | Privacy | Diagnostics

I agree that my usage behaviour regarding the Thermomix® may be tracked by Vorwerk International & Co. KmG, Switzerland and transferred to Vorwerk, LLC and to my Thermomix® Advisor (all hereinafter referred to as “Vorwerk”) and that Vorwerk may analyze my usage behaviour in order to improve the products and services and to provide me with content and offers matching my possible interests.

In case I have given my prior consent to the tracking and analysis on Cookidoo® according to section 4.4 of the Privacy Policy, Vorwerk may link the Thermomix® tracking data with my Cookidoo® tracking data for the aforementioned purposes.

Further details are set out in section 4.5 of the Privacy Policy. I can disable (and re-enable) this option at any time by changing my privacy settings under Account | Data usage.

**4.5.7** In case of using TM6 you can find the exact wording of your consent declaration under Account | Data usage

**4.5.8** When using the TM5 device you can withdraw your consent at any time with future effect by changing your privacy settings on the Thermomix® in the settings menu Settings | Privacy | Diagnostics and usage on the Thermomix®. In addition, to withdraw your consent effectively when using TM5 device, it is necessary that you successfully synchronize your Thermomix® with Cookidoo® after changing the settings.

**4.5.9** When using the TM6 device you can withdraw your consent at any time with future effect by changing your privacy settings on the Thermomix® in the settings menu Settings | Privacy | Data usage and usage on the Thermomix® or you change your Data usage settings on your profile under Account | Data usage

### 5 Customer Care

**5.1** When contacting customer care, we may collect certain data. Depending on the type of contact desired and type of requests received, such data can vary from being related to fixing a technical problem to data protection requests such as to access data or deletion of data. If necessary, we may also process data described in the sections 2.4.1, 2.5.1, 2.5.2, 3.4.2, 4.4.2, 4.5.2. in order to address your requests.

**5.2** The foregoing data will be used in order to fulfil the specific customer care request.

**5.3** The foregoing data is processed on the legal basis of the performance of a contract (Art. 6 (1) b GDPR); business purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(d) CCPA).

### 6 Payment Data

**6.1** When purchasing products or services on the Platform, you will have to submit payment information in order to allow processing of payments (depending on the payment method, e.g. a credit card number or PayPal). Your payment will be processed via the third-party payment provider Adyen, Simon Carmiggeltstraat 6-50, 011 DJ Amsterdam, The Netherlands.

**6.2** In order to file a proper invoice, the following data will be requested (\* = required data):

* Title
* First and Last Name
* Postal address
* Country
* IP address

**6.3** The foregoing data will be used in order to process the purchase. Such data is processed on the legal basis of the performance of a contract (Art. 6 (1) b GDPR); business purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(d) CCPA).

**6.4** Vorwerk International is required to adhere to tax legal obligation to verify customer's country of residence using the IP address to determine the geographical location where the customer's device is located. Such data is processed on the legal basis of compliance with a legal obligation to which the controller is subject (Art. 6 (1) c GDPR); business purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(d) CCPA).

### 7 Email Marketing

**7.1** Vorwerk International provides information on special offers and discount promotions from time to time via email. In the marketing emails, you will be provided with information on the Vorwerk Group Companies, their products and current offers and surveys, provided that you have registered for it.

**7.2** When agreeing to the reception of marketing emails, the following data will be processed:

* First and Last Name
* Email address
* Membership status
* Registered devices
* Country of residence
* Subscription type

**7.3** The foregoing data is used by the Vorwerk Group Companies in order to provide marketing emails which suit your possible interests (e.g. information on these companies, their products and current offers and surveys).

**7.4** You can unsubscribe from marketing emails at any time, either by de-registering from this service on Cookidoo®, or by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the end of each marketing email.

**7.5** You can find the exact wording of your consent declaration under Account | Data usage

**7.6** The data outlined in this section is processed on the legal basis of consent (Art. 6 (1) a GDPR); commercial purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(f) CCPA).

### 8 Recipients of Personal Data

**8.1** When providing services to you, we may share personal data with persons acting on our behalf or otherwise involved in the transaction, including:

* Service providers with whom personal data is being shared
* Other business partners who provide services to us, such as

* IT hosting providers
* Communication service providers
* Payment services providers
* Customer service providers
* Marketing service providers

**8.2** The recipients of personal data listed above may be located outside of the European Economic Area and/or the United States. Where necessary and unless the country to which data is being transferred has been determined by the European Commission as a country with adequate level of protection, we require such recipients to comply with data protection measures such as standard contractual clauses, the offer of appropriate guarantees according to the guidelines of the European Commission.

**8.3** Synchronisation and Update of Customer Data between Vorwerk Group Companies

**8.3.1** The Vorwerk Group Companies intend to keep customer contact data up to date. The Thermomix® and the Platform are provided by different Vorwerk Group Companies. In case you do provide updated contact data to one of the Vorwerk Group Companies, we would like to be able to update this information at the other Vorwerk Group Company as well. In order to do so, we ask you for your consent to synchronize such data.

**8.3.2** In case you have given your consent for synchronisation of customer data between Vorwerk Group Companies, the following data will be exchanged between the Vorwerk Group Companies, to the extent such data exists:

* User account data as described in section 2.5.1
* Your Thermomix® or Cook-Key® serial number as described in section 2.6.1

**8.3.3** The foregoing data will be exchanged between and processed by the Vorwerk Group Companies in order to keep their databases up to date. A further processing will only take place where legally permitted, e.g. processed for tracking of usage behaviour in case of additional consent subject to section 4 or marketing via emails in case of additional consent subject to section 7.

**8.3.4** You can withdraw your consent at any time by changing your privacy settings on the Platform in the Thermomix® user account. Go to “Data Usage” listed in the “Account” and move the bar to withdraw permission.

**8.3.5** You can find the exact wording of your consent under Account | Data usage

**8.3.6** The data outlined in this section is processed on the legal basis of consent (Art. 6 (1) a GDPR); commercial purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(f) CCPA).

**8.4** Data sharing with law enforcement authorities

**8.4.1** We might be obliged to transfer personal data to law enforcement authorities within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) c GDPR; business purposes (C.C. § 1798.140(d) CCPA).

**8.4.2** Vorwerk International reserves the right to share information relevant for the purpose of prevention and prosecution of criminal acts in case we observe any illegal behaviour relating to usage of the Platform or Thermomix® that serves our legitimate interest to protect our business and other users.

### 9 Your Rights

**9.1** Right of Access (Art. 15 GDPR) (C.C. §§ 1798.100, 1798.110 and 1798.115 CCPA)

You have the right to request confirmation as to whether Vorwerk International processes your personal data and where that is the case, that Vorwerk International provides you with access to, and information on the data stored by Vorwerk International with regard to your person or your pseudonym.

**9.2** Right to Rectification (Art. 16 GDPR) (C.C. § 1798.106 CCPA)

You have a right in respect of the correction of data in case your personal data collected is inaccurate.

**9.3** Right to Erasure (Art 17 GDPR) (C.C. § 1798.105 CCPA)

**9.3.1** You have the right to request erasure of personal data without undue delay under certain circumstances. Such circumstances may be e.g. if your personal data is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or if you withdraw consent on which our processing is based according to Art. 6 (1) a GDPR and where there is no other legal ground for processing.

**9.3.2** You can completely delete your user account on the Platform. For this purpose, simply send an email with the subject “delete my profile” to [dpo@vorwerk.ch](mailto:dpo@vorwerk.ch). Please note that use of Cookidoo® and the App will no longer be possible once the user account has been deleted.

**9.3.3** You can furthermore delete the following data:

* Data stored on the Thermomix® by using the factory reset function in the settings menu of the Thermomix®
* Network settings on your Thermomix® that is connected with the Internet by using the network reset function in the settings menu of the Thermomix®
* Recipes stored on the Thermomix® or on the Cook-Key® by using the reset function in the settings menu of the Thermomix®

**9.4** Right to Restriction on Processing (Art. 18 GDPR) (C.C. §§ 1798.120 CCPA)

You have the right to obtain a restriction of processing under certain circumstances. Such circumstance may be e.g. when you think that your personal data is not accurate or if we do not need the personal data for the original purpose of the processing but you need us to keep such data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

**9.5** Right to Data Portability (Art. 20 GDPR) (C.C. §§ 1798.100 and 1798.130 CCPA)

Under certain circumstances, you have the right to receive your personal data you have provided us with, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and you have the right to transmit that information to another controller without hindrance or ask us to do so.

**9.6** Right to Objection to Processing (Art. 21 GDPR) (C.C. §§ 1798.120 CCPA)

You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data under certain circumstances, in particular if we process your personal data on the legal basis of legitimate interests (Art. 6 (1) f GDPR) or if we use your personal data for marketing purposes.

**9.7** Right to Withdraw Consent (C.C. §§ 1798.120 and 135 CCPA)

**9.7.1** Where we process your personal data on the basis of consent you gave us within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) a GDPR, you have a right to withdraw that consent at any time. Please note that withdrawal of consent does not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

**9.7.2** For specific instructions on how to withdraw consent, please do also see

* section 4, in particular the sections 4.4.7 and 4.5.8 concerning the tracking of usage behaviour on the Platform and on your Thermomix®
* section 7.4 concerning how to unsubscribe from marketing emails
* section 8.3.4 concerning the synchronisation of customer data between Vorwerk Group Companies

**9.8** How to Exercise Your Data Protection Rights

For questions about the collection, processing or use of your personal data, the disclosure, correction, blocking or deletion of data or objection to a particular processing of data, data portability please contact the data protection officer via the contact information provided below in section 13.

**9.9** Right to lodge a complaint

**9.9.1** You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the member state of your habitual residence.

**9.9.2** If you are not satisfied with any aspect of data processing of your personal data by Vorwerk International, we would like to understand and discuss it with you and learn how can we improve the situation. Please feel free to contact us through the contact information provided below in section 13. Nonetheless, you may submit a complaint to the local data protection supervisory authority.

### 10 Data Security

At Vorwerk International we have implemented appropriate technical and organisational measures to prevent accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorised disclosure of, or access to, personal data transmitted, stored or otherwise processed.

### 11 Retention and Deletion of Data by Vorwerk International

**11.1** We store your personal data and other information (e.g. accounting data related to your purchases) for as long as necessary to provide our services to you, to enable you to use our websites and our products, to comply with applicable laws (including those regarding document retention), to resolve disputes with any parties and otherwise as necessary to allow us to conduct our business. As a consequence, we delete personal data as soon as it is no longer necessary for the aforementioned purposes.

**11.2** In case the processing is based on consent and you withdraw your consent, we will delete or anonymize your personal data without undue delay after the withdrawal, unless there is a legal basis to retain the data.

**11.3** If we store personal data for the only purpose of compliance with laws on document retention, we will store this personal data in archive mode. This means that the access to this personal data is strictly limited to those persons who might need access in order to comply with the aforementioned laws.

**11.4** The criteria we use to determine the periods for retaining your personal data include the retention requirements under applicable laws, regulations and our operational requirements, such as account maintenance, enabling customer relationship management and responding to legal claims, complaints and regulatory and law enforcement requests. If you have a question about a specific retention period for certain types of personal data we process, please contact us through the contact information provided below in section 13.

### 12 Status of the Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy was updated in March 2022. We reserve the right to amend the notice from time to time in case there are any changes to data processing. In case the Privacy Policy has been updated, we will take steps to inform you of the update by appropriate means, such as through a notification shown when logging on to your account or other means in case they are more suitable (e.g. email).

### 13 Data Protection Officer

You may contact the data protection officer of Vorwerk International at

Vorwerk International & Co. KmG  
Verenastrasse 39  
CH-8832 Wollerau  
Schweiz  
Vorwerk’s International EU representative

Vorwerk SE & Co. KG

Mühlenweg 17-37

42270 Wuppertal

Germany

© Copyright 2024

* [Report Content](javascript:void(0))

language English
